Christina L Bayley

Woodbury, NJ 08096 | christinabayley@comcast.net

Overview

Resourceful, driven, enthusiastic, self-motivated ERP and CRM systems expert with a strong relational database background. Solid business, technical, management, and presentation skills. Very detailed oriented with enhanced logical, critical, and analytical thinking skills. Proficient in translating users' needs and business requirements to technical terms. Passionate ability to analyze business processes and save time and money through system automation. Certifications in Full Stack Web Development, Microsoft Dynamics, Project Management and Microsoft Office.

Technical Skills | Certifications

SAP Business One • SAP by Design • Boyum • Amazon Web Services (AWS): Lambda Apps, RDS and Dynamo databases • MS Dynamics*: D365 v9.1, 9.0, 8.2, 8.1, .& 8.0, CRM 2016, 2015, 2013, 2011, 4.0 (online & on-premise) • Visual Studio • Visual Studio Code • Typescript • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • APIs (using and creating) • JSON • Console Apps • C# • rdl Reporting • .net Core • Azure: Logic Apps, Virtual Servers, Cosmos Databases, Function Apps • ClickDimensions* • Marketo • SQL Server (Management Studio, Reporting Services, BIDS) • MySQL • Report Builder 3.0 • IT Glue • Simego (Data Sync/ Ouvvi) • Scribe • Atlassian Jira • Trello • Git Extensions • Github • Harvest Time Tracking • JD Edwards Enterprise One, 7.3, 6.2 • AS/400 O/S and Queries • Advanced Crystal Reports • Business Objects Universe Design and Data Integrator • Business Objects 2008 Edge Suite • Advanced/Expert MS Office* Professional

Experience

Stellar One Consulting (S1C)

Lake Forest, CA

Jan 2020 – present

Senior Application Developer

- Support the company's mission to deliver a frictionless cloud platform that increases operational effectiveness and facilitates informed decision-making.
- Help the S1C team to lead the total disruption of the way ERP software is packaged, implemented, and supported.
- Work with the S1C team to help wherever needed whether it be with implementations, project management, Crystal Reports, Two-Minute Tips videos, queries, training, or coding.
- Future plans to build a customer portal where clients can self-serve and manage their own integrations with simple options and drop-and-drag features.

Beringer Technology Group

Maple Shade, NJ

May 2017 – Dec 2019

Implementation Specialist / Technical Architect (May 2017 – present)

- Technical lead on several projects. Managed configuration, development, and integration aspects as required. Leed several of Beringer's larger projects as well as an on-going XRM project.
- Developed Dynamics Best Practice model for Beringer and their clients. Performed a seven-session boot camp for internal employees surrounding best practice for Dynamics configuration items. Used documentation developed for boot camp to perform Webinars for Beringer's clients and prospects.
- Acted as a liaison between project manager and implementation team to keep everyone informed of clients' requirements.
- Acted as a lead/mentor to other implementation specialists.
- Attended and managed client meetings for configuration and data integration as needed.
- Participated in prospect client design sessions to configure and deliver customized demos of Microsoft Dynamics.
- Participated in design sessions to consider technical design of desired system. Analyzed client business processes to identify
 opportunities for improvements, performed gap analysis, documented and translated business requirements into wellarchitected technical specifications and solutions.
- Participated in data sessions to consider how data will migrate and/or integrate between systems.

- Developed, maintained, and managed internal process for alpha, beta, system, and client testing for implementations.
- Developed and maintained templates for documenting all aspects of implementations including general configurations,
 JavaScript, custom workflow plugins, and data integrations.
- Utilized Azure for implementations where needed.
- Deeply researched Azure as a data integration and migration replacement tool for Scribe.
- Helped manage and maintain Beringer's managed D365 solution (CRM for Distribution).
- Provided end-user, super-user, and admin training to clients as required for projects.
- Wrote internal SOPs as needed and managed them in IT Glue.
- As part of the quoting processes, provided estimates, created proposals, and worked with clients throughout the sales process.
- Posted regular blogs on beringer.net to help drive sales.
- Participated in the local CRMUG chapter by attending and presenting when needed.
- Used Microsoft resources to keep up-to-date on the latest technologies and share with the internal implementation team.

AmeriQuest Business Services

Cherry Hill, NJ

Jan 2011 – May 2017

CRM Systems Analyst (Jan 2013 - April 2017)

- Currently managing upgrade from CRM 2011 to CRM 2016.
- Use DataSync to automate data between systems as well as within CRM. Use Ouvvi web application to run DataSync projects via triggers.
- Use Jira application to keep a record of all issues, tasks, bugs, and enhancements related to day-to-day job functions as well
 as projects.
- Provide advanced dashboards and reports using CRM functionality as well as SQL Report Builder.
- Write and manage SQL queries and stored procedures.
- Fully customized Case entity in CRM to accommodate Service Desk's needs.
- Developed CRM integration with TFS and later with Jira for Developers.
- Created a Data Warehouse in SQL to house backup of CRM data as well as to provide a centralized location for outside systems to access CRM data.
- Fully manage the CRM system for all users and other support staff members.
- Automate tasks regularly based on business needs to save time and money.
- Work with Marketo and ClickDimensions marketing automation solutions.

CRM Administrator (Jan 2011 – Jan 2013)

- Fully administered and managed the Dynamics CRM system.
- Personally upgraded the system (and all components) from 4.0 to 2011 during the Summer/Fall of 2012.
- Re-wrote JavaScript libraries for all entities to accommodate requirements/changes for CRM 2011.
- Developed and managed reporting requirements for business.
- Determined needs/solutions for better automation for current business processes.
- Managed and handled all system customizations.
- Supported 200 250 users on a daily basis.
- Provided end-user training as-needed.

EP Henry Corporation

Woodbury, NJ

Oct 2008 - Jan 2011

JD Edwards / IT Business Analyst

- Implemented and maintained Dynamics CRM 4.0 for sales, marketing, manufacturing, and quality assurance departments.
- Maintained and customized CRM through application tools as well as writing customized JavaScript.
- Assisted/supported business users with processes in JDE Enterprise One software through troubleshooting and analysis.
- Created documentation and provided end-user training.
- Maintained data integrity through the use of SQL queries and Crystal Reports.
- Created and maintained library of Crystal Reports used by end-users.
- Created and maintained Business Objects Universes for Web Intelligence ad-hoc end-user report design.
- Setup new modules within JDE Enterprise One software with assistance of business process owners.

American Water Voorhees, NJ Aug 2001 – Sept 2008

Senior Business Reporting Analyst (Jan 2005 – Sept 2008)

Acted as a liaison between assigned functional departments and ITS department for various reporting issues and requests.

- Formulated and defined report scope and objectives through research and fact-finding combined with an understanding of business systems and industry requirements.
- Assisted business partners and internal ITS staff in the areas of user skills, maintenance, training, documentation, and troubleshooting reports.
- Maintained an up-to-date awareness of current business applications.
- Analyzed business reporting problems and developed technical design documentation for solutions.
- Used business knowledge and understanding of business systems to assist users and developers in formulating reporting solutions.
- Used various reporting tools (AS/400 queries, Orcom reports, Crystal reports, JD Edwards reports) to provide solutions.

Business Support Analyst | Shared Services Center (Aug 2001 – Dec 2004)

- Provided business and technical assistance for JD Edwards, RVI, Windows, and MS Office Professional applications to business partners.
- Analyzed and resolved issues in an efficient and timely manner via telephone, e-mail, Clarify, and HP OpenView.
- Gathered requirements, designed, tested, implemented, and maintained a variety of reports via Dream Writer, FASTR, World Writer, and AS/400 Queries.
- Assisted with financial, operating data, planning, and fixed assets report restructuring projects.
- Developed material and delivered training classes for JD Edwards overview, Printing from JD Edwards, World Writer report writing I and II, and Executing and Changing Standard Reports. Instructed over 200 in classroom settings as well as one-on-one training for various subjects in regards to JD Edwards on an as-needed basis.
- Involved in over six months of in-depth SAP Financial and Cost Controlling module training.
- Created macros in Visual Basic to perform multiple functions in JD Edwards via MS Excel spreadsheets to ensure efficiency
 of data entry and integrity as well as to eliminate manual data entry.

GlaxoSmithKline Philadelphia, PA May 1998 – Aug 2001

Financial Systems Administrator | Shared Financial Systems Helpdesk

- Provided all aspects of JD Edwards technical and business support over the phone and hands-on.
- Maintained a call log of all inquiries via an MS Access database.
- Generated metric analysis and quality assurance reports.
- Maintained and monitored all user security and profiles to ensure system integrity.
- Developed and maintained training manuals for JD Edwards and other proprietary software.
- Maintained training schedules and instructed all group and one-on-one training sessions.
- Successfully developed and delivered training to all new employees brought in via merger.
- Created and maintained several different styles of reports for various customers in JDE via World Writer, Dream Writer,
 FASTR, and AS/400 Queries.
- Worked with the JD Edwards programming department; wrote basic SQL statements and edited RPG programs.
- Created and maintained several MS Access databases decreasing manual processes and reducing labor costs for multiple departments. Databases included an internal catering service ordering system, auditing for procurement card administrator, and call-tracking for the helpdesk.

Certifications

October 2018 MB2-716: Microsoft Dynamics 365 Customization & Configuration

- Completed MBS training self-study of courses pertaining to certification.
- Received certification on first attempt.

September 2017 MB2-710: Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2016 Online Deployment

- Completed MBS training self-study of courses pertaining to certification.
- Received certification on first attempt.

May 2017

ClickDimensions Certification

Completed required ClickDimensions training and completed test to acquire certification.

October 2006

Microsoft Office Specialist Master Certification

- Completed required exams to acquire Master Certification for MS Office 2003.
- Exams included: MS Excel Expert, MS Word Expert, MS Access, and MS PowerPoint.

May 2006

Project Management Certification

University of Phoenix

- Completed all required classes for Project Management Certification with a 3.72 GPA.
- Classes centered on designing a project plan, managing a strategic portfolio, procurement and risk management, project estimating, and leading/ managing projects. Final class focused on the entire project life cycle from project conception through project closeout.

Education

May 2020 - Oct 2020

University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

Penn LPS Coding Bootcamp Certificate

online

- Intensive bootcamp dedicated to designing and building web applications.
- Skills learned include: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, React.

Aug 2007 - Dec 2016

Pennsylvania State University

World Campus

- Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science and Information Technology courses.
- Dean's List with GPA of 3.8.

Nov 1999 - Dec 2006

University of Phoenix

Philadelphia, PA

- Business Administration courses.
- Associates Degree equivalent credits (80+ credits).

March 1998 – May 1998

CoreTech Consulting Group

King of Prussia, PA

- Support Analyst training program.
- Forty-nine hours of classroom instruction in language and software skills.
- Developed problem solving and customer service skills.
- Intense review of common MS Office suite questions and helpdesk techniques.

June 1993 – June 1995

Harrisburg Area Community College

Harrisburg, PA

Majored in Business Management with a minor in Communications.

References

Available upon request.